Inventory of the William John Fellner Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
William John Fellner papers
1938-1985
Bulk, 1975-1983
87005
Hoover Institution Archives
67 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 2 phonotape cassettes (27.3 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, conference papers, reports, studies, testimony, charts, and statistics related to economic conditions and governmental economic policy in the United States, and laissez-faire economic theory, including particularly questions of unemployment, inflation, and monetary policy.
Fellner, William John, 1905-
Access
Collection is open for research. Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1987.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Collections
Milton Friedman Papers, Hoover Institution Archives Gottfried Haberler Papers, Hoover Institution Archives Fritz Machlup Papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1905 Born, Budapest, Hungary
1929 Ph.D. in economics, University of Berlin
1929-1938 Partner in family business in Hungarian manufacturing industry
1939-1952 Member of economics faculty at University of California, Berkeley
1942 Author, A Treatise on War Inflation
1946 Author, Monetary Policies and Full Employment
1949 Author, Competition Among the Few: Oligopoly and Similar Market Structures
1952-1973 Professor of economics, Yale University
1956 Author, Trends and Cycles in Economic Activity: An Introduction to Problems of Economic Growth
1956-1958 Member, Executive Committee, American Economic Association
1960 Author, Emergence and Content of Modern Economic Analysis
1965 Author, Probability and Profit: A Study of Economic Behavior Along Bayesian Lines
1969 President, American Economic Association
1970-1983 Adviser, Brookings Panel on Economic Activity
1972 Author, with Phillip Cagan, Economic Policies and Inflation in the Sixties
1973 Author, with Phillip Cagan and Marten Estey, A New Look at Inflation: Economic Policy in the Early 1970s
1973-1975 Member, Council of Economic Advisors
1973-1983 Resident scholar, American Enterprise Institute
1976 Author, Towards a Reconstruction of Macroeconomics
1983 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers document the career of economist William John Fellner through correspondence, speeches and writings, conference papers, reports, studies, testimony, charts, and statistics related to economic conditions and governmental economic policy in the United States, and laissez-faire economic theory, including questions of unemployment, inflation, and monetary policy.
Feller immigrated to the United States in 1938, joining the economics faculty at the University of California, Berkeley. He was a professor at Yale University from 1952 to 1973, after which he became a member of the Council of Economic Advisors. The Biographical file includes material from Fellner's memorial service, as well as his Festschrift.
The Correspondence contains Fellner's letters to and from economists, including scholars associated with the American Enterprise Institute, such as Phillip Cagan and Gottfried Haberler. These files often contain preliminary drafts of scholarly papers sent as enclosures.
Fellner wrote about a variety of topics in economics, including inflation, full employment, balance of payments, oligopoly, and tax indexing. The Speeches and writings include typescripts of Fellner's last published book, Towards a Reconstruction of Macroeconomics, as well as typescripts and proofs of his scholarly articles.
Fellner was a resident scholar at the American Enterprise Institute, where he directed the Contemporary Economic Problems project to publish annual volumes on topics in economics. The American Enterprise Institute file includes correspondence and papers submitted to the Contemporary Economic Problems project, as well as a transcript of a presentation given by Friedrich August von Hayek in 1975.
After retiring from his professorial work, Fellner was involved in several economics organizations and boards. The Subject file contains correspondence, memoranda, and conference papers related to groups such as the Brookings Panel on Economic Activity, the Congressional Budget Office, the Council of Economic Advisors, and the Gold Commission.
A significant portion of the collection contains Writings by others, mainly in the form of conference papers or preliminary drafts send to Fellner by other economists.
The collection includes Sound recordings of the Public Policy Forums program. In a recording from 1977, Henry Aaron and Rudolph Penner discuss ways to avoid bankruptcy of the Social Security program. A recording from 1982 contains an economic policy discussion with Phillip Cagan, William Fellner, Rudolph Penner, and Herbert Stein.
Source: Connell, Carol M. Reforming the World Monetary System: Fritz Machlup and the Bellagio Group. London: Pickering & Chatto, 2013.
Council of Economic Advisers (U.S.); Economics.; Economists.; Employment (Economic theory); Inflation (Finance); Monetary policy.; Phonotapes.
- Biographical file, 1975-1985
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes materials from Fellner's memorial service, awards, clippings, and Fellner's Festschrift.
  - American Enterprise Institute personal file, 1979-1983 (Box 15)
    Includes outline of activities at the American Enterprise Institute, correspondence, financial documents, and memoranda on Fellner's death
  - Appointment book, 1975 (Box 68)
    Includes memoranda
  - Bernhard-Harms Award, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Clippings about Fellner
    - 1978 (Box 34)
    - 1980 (Box 44)
    - 1981 (Box 44)
    - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Festschrift, Economic Progress, Private Values and Public Policy: Essays in Honor of William Fellner, 1977 (Box 12)
  - Memorial file, 1982-1985 (Box 1, 32)
    Includes biography, bibiliography, and photographs
  - Obituaries and memorial addresses, 1983 (Box 67)
  - Plaque, National Economists Club, 1979 (Box 64)
    Presented to Fellner in appreciation of his service as a member of the board of governors from 1976 to 1978.
  - Resumes, biographies, bibliographies, and photographs and negatives of Fellner, 1976-1982 (Box 15)
  - Travel file, 1976-1977 (Box 53)
- Correspondence, 1972-1984
  Contains correspondence with economists and other scholars organized chronologically or alphabetically by individual or organization. Includes academic papers enclosed or filed with correspondence.
  - Chronological file, 1978-1983
    - 1978 (Box 21)
    - 1979 (Box 21)
    - 1980 (Box 21)
    - 1981 (Box 27)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 27)
  - Alphabetical file I, 1972-1973 (Box 12-13)
    - A to R, 1972-1973 (Box 13)
      Includes correspondence with Fritz Machlup
    - S to Z, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Alphabetical file II, 1975-1984
    - A, 1975-1983 (Box 66)
    - Ackley, Gardner, 1977-1980 (Box 17)
    - Arioli, Silvio, 1978 (Box 59)
    - B, 1975-1983 (Box 16, 29)
    - Bailey, Martin, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Balassa, Bela, 1975-1982 (Box 15)
    - Baroody, William, 1981-1983 (Box 15)
    - Bator, Francis, 1981 (Box 33)
    - Bauer, Peter, 1976-1981 (Box 35)
    - Bennett, Jack, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Bennett, William, 1975 July (Box 1)
    - Bernstein, Edward, 1974-1977 (Box 35)
    - Bernstein, Peter, 1976 (Box 35)
    - Bradford, David, 1975-1976 (Box 35)
    - Bradley, Gene E., 1975-1976 (Box 35)
    - Brookings Institution, 1975-1981 (Box 15)
    - Brown, Weir, 1981 (Box 15)
    - Burns, Arthur, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
    - C, 1976-1983 (Box 16)
    - Cagan, Phillip
      - 1976-1978 (Box 15)
      - 1981 (Box 6)
    - Carson, Carol, 1982 (Box 1)
      Memoranda concerning Ruggles study
    - Chipman, John S., 1978-1980 (Box 15)
    - Chiswick, Barry R., 1975-1983 (Box 15)
    - Civil Service Commission, 1976 (Box 15, 61)
    - Cochrane, John, 1982 (Box 15, 60)
    - Colander, David C., 1978-1979 (Box 33)
    - Congress, 1975 (Box 33)
    - Congressional Budget Office, 1975-1983 (Box 35)
    - D, 1977-1982 (Box 33)
    - Dadd, C. Mark, 1982 (Box 36, 42)
    - David, Paul, 1982 (Box 36)
    - DeWald, William, 1982 (Box 6)
    - E, 1978-1982 (Box 41)
    - Ellis, Howard, 1978-1983 (Box 44)
    - Engels, Wolfram, 1979 (Box 44)
    - Erb, Richard, 1979-1983 (Box 56)
    - F, 1975-1983 (Box 56)
      Includes correspondence with Edgar Feige
    - Fand, David, 1975-1981 (Box 56)
    - Feldstein, Martin S., 1975-1983 (Box 67)
    - Fellner, Marcelo, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Fiedler, Edgar R., 1976-1977 (Box 56)
    - Field, Tom, memorandum, 1975 July (Box 1)
    - Flaim, Paul O., 1978 (Box 59)
    - Fleischer, Robert, 1976 (Box 61)
    - Frankel, S. Herbert, 1979-1981 (Box 56)
    - Friedman, Benjamin M., 1980-1982 (Box 50)
    - Friedman, Charles, 1980-1981 (Box 32)
    - G, 1977-1982 (Box 26)
    - Georgetown University, 1978 (Box 27)
    - German embassy correspondence, Ruyter-Volkswagen Foundation, 1978-1979 (Box 28)
    - German Order of Merit, 1979 (Box 27)
      Includes speech by Fellner
    - Giersch, Herbert, 1975-1983 (Box 6, 28)
    - Gradison, Bill, 1978-1981 (Box 29)
    - Greenfield, Harry, 1976-1978 (Box 29)
    - Greenwald, Douglas, 1978-1979 (Box 29)
    - H, 1975-1982 (Box 28-29)
    - Haberler, Gottfried
      - Correspondence with Fellner, undated (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with others (Box 1, 2, 5)
        Includes correspondence on tax indexing
    - Hamburger, Michael J., 1977-1981 (Box 29)
    - Harris, Lowell C., 1975-1978 (Box 29)
    - Hogan, Warren, 1979-1980 (Box 29)
    - Hoover Institution Archives, 1979-1984 (Box 3)
    - I, 1975-1980 (Box 29)
    - International Monetary Fund, 1980-1983 (Box 29)
      Includes writing by Fellner from the International Monetary System Under Stress AEI Conference
    - J, 1975-1981 (Box 29)
    - Jaszi, George, 1981-1983 (Box 1, 6)
      - 1975-1983 (Box 27)
        Includes business reports
      - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
      - 1983 (Box 6, 37)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1978 August (Box 1)
    - Junz, Helen, 1977-1978 (Box 28)
    - K, 1975-1983 (Box 32, 34)
    - Kalchbrenner, John (Box 53)
      Includes enclosures on money demand and velocity to prepare for testimony
    - Kalman, R. E., 1979-1983 (Box 3, 34)
    - Kato, Koichi, 1983 (Box 50)
    - Katz, Samual, 1976-1981 (Box 34)
    - Kemeny, Stephen, 1979-1980 (Box 34)
    - Kemp-Roth and Steiger bills, 1978 (Box 34)
    - Kendrick, John W., 1976-1977 (Box 2, 42)
    - Kudlow, Lawrence A., undated (Box 34)
    - L, 1977-1982 (Box 28)
    - Lademann, John R., 1979-1982 (Box 27)
    - Lamfalussy, Alexandre, 1977 (Box 27)
    - Larkins, Daniel, 1978-1982 (Box 27)
    - Lehrman, Lewis E., 1975-1980 (Box 27)
    - Leijonhufvud, Axel, 1978-1982 (Box 34)
    - Levin, Jay, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Levitan, Sar A., 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - M, 1975-1982 (Box 17)
    - Mc, 1976-1983 (Box 17)
    - MacLaury, Bruce, 1977-1982 (Box 17)
    - McCracken, Paul W., 1975-1978 (Box 16)
    - Meltzer, Allan H., 1979-1981 (Box 16)
    - Mitchell, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Miyamota, Kunio, 1979-1981 (Box 17)
    - Molnar, Ferenc, 1977 (Box 17)
    - Moore, Geoffrey H., 1978 (Box 17)
    - Mundell, Robert A., 1975-1979 (Box 17)
    - Murphy, J. Carter, 1975-1981 (Box 17)
    - N, 1975-1982 (Box 16)
    - National Science Foundation, 1976-1981 (Box 16)
    - Needham, James, 1974 (Box 39)
    - Nelson, Richard, 1976-1978 (Box 5, 16)
    - O, 1975-1982 (Box 44)
    - Okun, Arthur, 1975-1981 (Box 58)
    - P, 1975-1982 (Box 58)
    - Penner, Rudy J., 1978-1982 (Box 56)
    - Perlman, Mark, 1975-1983 (Box 53)
    - Peterson, William H., 1977-1978 (Box 53)
    - R, 1976-1981 (Box 24)
    - Reuss, Henry S., 1977 (Box 24)
    - Richter, Rudolf, 1977-1980 (Box 24)
    - Rottenberg, Irving, 1975 (Box 2)
    - S, 1975-1983 (Box 22, 33)
    - Scitovsky, Tibor, 1982-1983 (Box 22)
    - Seidman, Frank E., 1974-1976 (Box 24)
      Includes meeting minutes of board of trustees of the Frank E. Seidman Distinguished Award in Policial Economy
    - Shadow European Economic Policy Committee and Shadow Open Market Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 22, 50)
      Includes letters of Allan Meltzer and Karl Brunner
    - Shannon, John, 1977-1980 (Box 22)
    - Shieh, Francis, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Simon, Julian L., 1977-1982 (Box 22)
    - Sinai, Michael, 1977-1978 (Box 22)
    - Shultz, George P., 1983 (Box 1, 30)
    - Skorov, Georgy, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Solomon, Robert, 1978-1983 (Box 22)
    - Stein, Herbert, 1982-1983 (Box 3, 23)
    - Sunley, Emil M., 1975 (Box 2)
    - T, 1975-1983 (Box 23)
      Includes correspondence with Robert Triffin
    - Tax indexation, 1975, 1981 (Box 22, 29)
      Includes correspondence with William L. Armstrong
    - Taylor, John B., 1978 (Box 22)
    - Thimmesch, Nick, 1983 (Box 3)
    - Tobin, James, 1977 (Box 22)
    - Toshida, Seiichi, 1983 (Box 36)
    - Tsiang, S. C., 1977-1981 (Box 22)
    - Tumlir, Jim, 1975-1981 (Box 21)
    - Turek, Joan Lee, 1976 (Box 61)
    - U, 1978-1983 (Box 25)
    - U.S. News and World Report, 1981 (Box 25, 28)
      Includes interview of Fellner
    - V, 1979-1982 (Box 23)
    - Van Duyne, Carl, 1975-1976 (Box 23)
    - Vaubel, Roland, 1979 (Box 23)
    - Volkswagen Foundation, 1979 (Box 24)
    - Von Furstenberg, George, 1977-1983 (Box 23)
    - W, 1975-1982 (Box 23)
    - Wachter, Micahel L., 1978 (Box 24)
    - Wallich, Henry C., 1976-1981 (Box 24, 42)
    - Wall Street Journal, 1977-1983 (Box 21)
    - Weidenbaum, Murray, 1976-1981 (Box 21)
    - White, William H., 1975 (Box 21)
    - Whitman, Marina, 1975-1979 (Box 21)
    - Willett, Thomas, 1978-1981 (Box 14, 25, 41)
    - Witteveen, Johannes H., 1977 (Box 49)
    - Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1975-1978 (Box 49)
    - X, Y, Z, 1978-1982 (Box 49)
- Speeches and writings, 1938-1983
  Includes typescripts and galley proofs of Fellner's writings on economics.
  - "Appraising the Cost of Disinflation," draft, undated (Box 2)
    Paper for inclusion in Egon Sohmen Festschrift
  - Article in The Public Stake in Union Power, undated (Box 5)
  - "Comment on Charles Schultze's Papers: A Different Interpretation of the Same and Further Facts", undated (Box 28)
  - "Comments on Concepts of an 'Undisturbed Path' of the Economy", undated (Box 6, 37, 47)
  - "The Core of the Controversy about Reducing Inflation: An Introductory Analysis", undated (Box 2)
  - "The Credibility Effect, Rational Expectations and the Contribution of the Gramlich Study to the Debate", undated (Box 30)
  - "A Critique of Fiscal Policies Based on the Conventional Concept of Potential Output", undated (Box 47)
  - Discussion of national income accounts conclusions, undated (Box 11)
    Most likely by Fellner
  - "Employment Policy, Money and Inflation", undated (Box 11)
  - "Failure of the M1 Approach in Monetary Theory: The Need to Look at Broader Aggregates," with Larkins, undated (Box 9, 37, 67)
  - "Gold: A Preliminary Survey of Findings and Conclusions," American Enterprise Institute, undated (Box 1)
  - "Inflationary Overtaxation: Our Confusing Record", undated (Box 55, 59)
  - "Macroeconomic Considerations Relating to the 1979 Budget", undated (Box 8)
  - "Memorandum on the Taxation of Corporate Revaluation Gains", undated (Box 58-59, 68)
  - "Money, Manpower and Inflation", undated (Box 1)
  - "Notes Which Professor Cagan May Want to Use With As Many Changes, Omissions, and Additions as He Prefers, When Presenting our Joint Position at Brookings", undated (Box 47)
  - "On Monetary-Policy Problems of Interest to Those Whose Decisions Are Complementary with Fed Policy," memorandum, undated (Box 35)
  - Preface to Contemporary Economic Problems, undated (Box 2)
  - "Production, Employment and Induced Innovations: Theoretical and Empirical Exploration of Growth Rates," introduction, part 1, and part 3, undated (Box 4)
  - "A Project on the Relation of Political Trends to Economic Analysis," draft, undated (Box 1, 37)
  - "Salient Features of Legislation That Would Incorporate the Main Suggestions of the Study: 'Correcting Taxes for Inflation'", undated (Box 9, 35, 55)
  - "Taxes in an Era of Rising Prices: In What Sense Indexation?", undated (Box 9, 31, 55)
  - "To the Valid Core of Rational Expectations," abstract and guide to the paper, undated (Box 1)
  - "Views Presented to the Gold Commission", undated (Box 14)
  - "Savings, Investment and the Problem of Neutral Money", 1938 April (Box 5)
  - "Average Cost Pricing and the Theory of Uncertainty", 1946 April (Box 5)
  - "Tax Program for Sustained Mobilization," with Butters et al., 1951 (Box 5)
  - "Maintaining and Restoring Balance in International Payments," with Machlup and Triffin, 1966 May (Box 5)
  - "Specific Interpretations of Learning by Doing", 1969 May (Box 5)
  - "Land in Fellner's Model of Economic Growth", 1970 (Box 5)
  - "Trends in the Activities Generating Technological Progress", 1970 (Box 5)
  - "Empirical Support for a Theory of Induced Innovations", 1971 (Box 5, 34)
  - "Phillips-type Approach or Acceleration?" reprint, 1971 (Box 34)
  - "Tensions at Full Utilization", 1972 (Box 5)
  - "Controlled Floating and the Confused Issue of Money Illusion", 1973 (Box 10, 12)
  - Speeches, Council of Economic Advisers, 1974 (Box 5, 66)
  - "A Strange Expansion", 1974 (Box 5)
  - "Discussion Paper Relating to the Shoven-Bulow Study", 1975 (Box 30)
  - Letter to the editor of the New York Times, 1975 (Box 59)
  - "Monetary Versus Monetarist Theories", 1975 (Box 9, 55)
  - "Revisiting the 'Austrian' Time Periods with Current Tax Policy in Mind," Conference on Tax Research 1975, Department of the Treasury (Box 5, 53, 55)
  - Testimony at the hearing of the Committee on the Budget of the United State Senate, 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Testimony Before the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives", 1975 (Box 51, 59, 64)
  - "Why Indexed Tax Systems Provide the Needed Frame of Reference," speech, U.S. Civil Service Commission Executive Seminar Center, 1975 (Box 58-59)
  - "Why We Must Insist on Exchagne-Rate Flexibility: Observations for the June 18th Conference at the Treasury", 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Comments and Discussion," Brookings Papers on Economic Activity, 1976 (Box 64)
  - "Comments on the Shoven-Bulow Paper", 1976 (Box 10, 20, 35)
  - "Criteria for Demand-Management Policy in View of Past Failures," preliminary draft, 1976 (Box 8)
  - "Interpretation of a Regularity in the Behavior of M2," Fellner and Dan Larkins, 1976-1977 (Box 42, 56, 67)
  - "Lessons From the Failure of Demand-Management Policies: A Look at the Theoretical Foundations", circa 1976 (Box 9, 37, 53)
  - Towards a Reconstruction of Macroeconomics
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 64)
      Includes letters from W. A. Johr and Robert Triffin
    - Typescripts, 1976 (Box 53, 57)
  - "Comments on Orley Ashenfelter's Paper," for Brookings Conference on November 30, 1977 (Box 10, 59)
  - "Desirable and Undesirable Types of Coordination: The Case Against Requiring Countries to Expand More Rapidly for 'Sharing the Oil Deficit'", 1977 (Box 5, 20, 35)
  - "Fewer Nonworkers and Yet More Unemployed in the Population", 1977 (Box 66)
  - "Gearing Demand Management to Supply Behavior in a Market Economy", 1977 (Box 2, 19)
  - Modern Market Economy, 1977-1978
    Project for the American Enterprise Institute to create a volume describing an economic program for a modern market economy. Fellner, Herbert Stein,and Hendrik Houthakker participated in the project.
    - General, 1977 (Box 61)
    - Background papers, 1977 (Box 36)
    - Chapter drafts, 1977-1978 (Box 11, 25)
    - Larkins, Dan, "Background Paper on Monetary and Fiscal Policy for Modern Market Economy Project", 1977 (Box 3, 25)
      American Enterprise Institute Modern Market Economy Project
    - Mead, Walter J., "Energy and the Environment", 1978 (Box 3)
  - "Money Supply and the Budget: Current and Future Problems of Demand Management", 1977 (Box 5, 21, 67)
  - "More Employment and Yet More Unemployment: Structural Factors Behind the Paradox", 1977 (Box 2, 48)
  - "Problems to Keep in Mind When It Comes to Tax Reform", 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Productivity Trends, Profitability and Uncertainties Facing Investors," draft, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Prospectus for "A Positive Program for A Modern Market Economy", 1977 (Box 1)
    Includes list of participants
  - "Schools of Thought In the Mainstream of American Economics," Hungarian Economic Association, 1977 (Box 11)
  - "Summary of Argument on the Uncertainty Expressing itself in the Valuation of Stocks," draft, 1977 (Box 1, 66)
  - "Why Unemployment Rates Have Been Climbing," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1977 (Box 47)
  - "Appraising the Cost of Disinflation", 1978 (Box 11)
  - "The Bearing of Risk Aversion on Movements of Spot and Forward Exchange Relative to the Dollar," Egon Sohmen festschrift, drafts and correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 13, 18, 25, 37, 55, 66)
  - "The Core of the Controversy About Reducing Inflation: Introductory Analysis Relating to Cagan's Study," preface to Contemporary Economic Problems, 1978 (Box 47)
  - "The Policy Position in Brief, Chapter on Demand Management", 1978 (Box 5)
  - "The Sliding Dollar: True and False Issues", 1978 (Box 11)
  - Statement of William Fellner, Marvin Kosters, and Herbert Stein before the National Commission, hearing transcript, 1978 (Box 51)
    Includes letter from Mark Rosenblum
  - "Structural Problems Behind Our Measured Unemployment Rates," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1978 (Box 47)
  - "Testimony Before the Subcommittee on Taxation and Debt Management of the Senate Finance Committee," hearings on tax indexation, 1978 (Box 51)
  - "American Household Wealth in an Inflationary Period," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1979 (Box 47)
  - "The Credibility Effect and Rational Expectations: Implications of the Gramlich Study", 1979 (Box 9, 37)
  - "Corporate Wealth, After-Tax Profit Rates, and the Weight of Contractual Interest in the Total Yield of Invested Capital," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1979 (Box 47)
  - "The Declining American Productivity Growth: An Introductory Note," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1979 (Box 47)
  - "Macro Economic Policies and Economic Performance: Exit the Seventies--Enter the Eighties", 1979 (Box 34)
  - "Market Responses to the Inflationary Trend: Changes in the Composition of American Household Wealth and in the Asset-Liability Position of Corporations," Economic Essays in Honour of Stephen Varga (Istvan Varga), 1979-1982 (Box 7)
    Includes correspondence
  - "The Nature of Governmental Involvement in Economic Affairs and Democracy's Prospect of Survival", 1979 (Box 67-68)
  - "Neo-Keynesianism, Monetarism, and the Short and Long Run," Lerner Festschrift, 1979 (Box 9)
  - "Produktivität und wirtschaftspolitisches Milieu in den Vereinigten Staaten," Neue Zürcher Zeitung, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Remarks at Public Policy Conference, 1979 (Box 39)
  - "Remarks by William Fellner at the Embassy of the Federal Republic of Germany on Receipt of the Commander's Cross of the German Order of Merit", 1979 (Box 27)
  - "Testimony Before the Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the United States Senate", 1979 (Box 51)
  - "Comment on the Paper by Messrs. Laird and Korb," American Enterprise Institute seminar, 1980 (Box 9)
  - "Corporate Asset Liability Decisions in View of the Low Market Valuation of Equity," Contemporary Economic Problems, 1980 (Box 25, 47, 55)
  - "Full Demand Disinflation in One Step and the Problem of Shock Reducers," part III, 1980 (Box 55)